<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>johnyeary.com/</title>
   
   <link>https://johnyeary.com</link>
   <description>A Caffeinated Java Developer.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Standards of Training, Certification, and Watchkeeping (STCW) 95 Ammended</title>
	  <link>//2010-04-03-standards-of-training-certification-and-watchkeeping-stcw-95-ammended.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2010-04-03T00:26:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2010-04-03-standards-of-training-certification-and-watchkeeping-stcw-95-ammended.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I need to take a number of certification/training courses which are required of all merchant mariner’s who sail in international waters. These standards were implemented by the International Maritime Organization (IMO) which is part of the United Nations. The US is signatory to the agreement, and the USCG is charged with making sure that all mariner’s are in compliance as required.</p>

<p>In my case, I need to have Basic Survival Training (BST) which includes basic fire prevention and fire fighting, personal survival techniques, personal safety and social responsibility, and first aid. This covers STCW A-VI/1-1 to 1-4.</p>

<p>I also needed Advanced Fire fighting (AFF) which covers STCW A-VI/3. This is a five day course generally which must be renewed every five years.</p>

<p>The Proficiency in Survival Craft and Rescue Boats (PSC/R) (Lifeboatman) is required of all deck and engineering officers. This satisfies the STCW A-VI/2, Table A-VI/2-1, 2-2 requirements.</p>

<p>I have been advised that I may need to take a Medical First Aid Provider course which will satisfy STCW A-VI/4, 4.1-4.3 and Table 4-1. I need to confirm this is indeed necessary. I understand this may be required to for a raise in grade from the support to the operational licenses as per USCG Policy Letter 01- 02.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>USCG Merchant Marine Physical</title>
	  <link>//2010-04-02-uscg-merchant-marine-physical.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2010-04-02T23:54:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2010-04-02-uscg-merchant-marine-physical.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>The only requirement for getting started in the US Merchant Marine is getting a CG-719 K/E physical. This physical is required to get a Merchant Mariners Document (MMD). I completed the CG-719 and CG-719 K/E physicals.</p>

<p>The CG-719 physical is an all encompassing complete physical. It includes an eye exam and check for color blindness, as well as, a hearing exam. You will need this exam if you want to apply for your license, or for any additional rating considerations so I recommend getting both forms completed and submitting them to the Regional Exam Center (REC) when you complete your MMD application.</p>

<p>When I was younger, I could read the eye charts from across the room. I know that my vision is not as good as when I was a younger man, but I still have 20/20 vision. I was so happy to get some reassurance that my vision is still “perfect”.</p>

<p>The hearing exam did me no favors. I found out that my hearing is fine which differs from my wife’s opinion on the subject. Perhaps that is the “subjective” part.</p>

<p>I had a routine annual physical from my regular physician, but this was far more comprehensive and made me feel much better about my overall health.</p>

<p>It did confirm I need to lose weight, but few Americans don’t need too! I have been working on that however.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Transportation Workers Identification Card (TWIC)</title>
	  <link>//2010-04-02-transportation-workers-identification-card-twic.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2010-04-02T23:43:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2010-04-02-transportation-workers-identification-card-twic.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>All maritime personnel are now required to get a TWIC card before they can get their Merchant Mariners Document (MMD) issued. The TWIC is issued by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA).</p>

<p>I found the process easy, but in some ways a silly bureaucratic quagmire. The form states that answering “YES” to the following questions will automatically disqualify you. Then they ask essentially if you are a terrorist. OK… If you were a terrorist would you answer “YES”. If you did, well you are the worst damn terrorist in the world and deserve to be laughed to death in prison.</p>

<p>Anyway, they ask additional questions about felonies and convictions, etc. Some of items were not necessarily disqualifying. As I sat in the TSA waiting room for my turn to be photographed and finger printed, I looked around the room. I wondered how many of the people in the room answered “YES” to those questions. I know I shouldn’t judge a book by its cover, but there were some folks with some prison tattoos sitting in there with me.</p>

<p>My real question for the TSA is why ask someone about felonies, etc. when you are going to do a National Agency Check (NAC) anyway. The criminal backgrounds would be apparent anyway. Are you doing a test to see if a felon would knowingly admit to being a felon, and if not you could throw him back in jail for falsifying his application?</p>

<p>I can understand asking those questions of a foreign national who may be applying since those national records may not be available to US agencies. Americans though? Perhaps you should streamline the process and ask them to declare any convictions in countries other that the US.</p>

<p>Anyway, I am a clean, coca-cola, baseball, mom’s apple pie, all American patriot so I had no issues getting a TWIC. Step one of getting my new MMD is complete.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>US Merchant Marine</title>
	  <link>//2010-04-02-us-merchant-marine.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2010-04-02T23:24:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2010-04-02-us-merchant-marine.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I am in the process of renewing my USCG 3rd Assistant Engineer - Unlimited license. The process is complex to say the least. I have been told a number of times already that I should not have let it expire. Since I let it expire, the process of getting a new one is much more complex.</p>

<p>I am going to do a series of blog posts on how to become a US Merchant Marine Engineering Officer once your license expires. This applies in general to anyone who wants to join the Merchant Marine.</p>

<p>I have decided to also work on my MCA (Maritime Coastguard Agency - UK) and RYA (Royal Yachting Association) credentials as well.</p>

<p>My ultimate goal is to renew my USCG engineering license, but I would also like to get my Masters license as well. For those who know me, I always want more. I want to be a Master Mariner who can operate on the bridge, or in the engine room.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
