<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>johnyeary.com/</title>
   
   <link></link>
   <description>A Caffeinated Java Developer.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Blog Migration</title>
	  <link>//2019-11-01-blog-migration.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2019-11-01T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2019-11-01-blog-migration.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>After a couple of years using Wordpress, I have found that constantly upgrading, broken plugins, managing a database, backups, and security certificates have brought me back to Github.</p>

<p>When I first started the blogging journey, I wanted a text editor which I could use to create my posts. Over the years, I have found myself using <a href="https://www.markdownguide.org/">Markdown</a> at first for my Github projects, and finally for all of my work. This includes taking all my notes using Markdown.</p>

<p>I decided to come back and take a look at GitHub, and reconsider my previous position of it not being the right fit for me. Today, I think it is a perfect fit. The platform has been enhanced, and a number of great templates have been created to make using it a lot easier. That said, a number of the templates are <strong>not</strong> non-technical user friendly. I have had some challenges getting the blog back off the ground using Github, but I think that the final results will be worth it.</p>

<p>Over the next few weeks, I will begin the slow process of migrating the old blog pages over to Github, and adding new content. As I begin this journey, I will tell you how I did it.</p>

<h2 id="decisions">Decisions</h2>

<p>If you are not comfortable in <a href="https://www.markdownguide.org/">Markdown</a> then using Github pages are not for you. You have to decide if you want to learn it, and use it. Otherwise the risk is that you will <strong>not</strong> blog which is the opposite of your objective.</p>

<p>If you have a blog already, then you need to decide if you want to do the work to migrate it. This could be an enormous undertaking if you have been doing it for years. It also could be something that you may not want to do. I have another blog <a href="http://javaevangelist.blogspot.com/">Java Evangelist John Yeary</a> which is quite large. I wrote it on Blogger, and decided that I <strong>did not</strong> want to move it. It was established, and profitible. I did decide years ago that I wanted to move it from a propietary platform and make it more “my own”. Thus I created a blog simply called John Yeary. That is the blog we are going to be migrating.</p>

<h2 id="first-steps">First Steps</h2>

<p>The first step in getting started in creating, or migrating a blog is to find a good template to use. You can go all-in on creating your own using, but even <a href="https://jekyllrb.com/">jekyll</a> uses a basic template called <em>minima</em> when you create a simple site using the tutorial.</p>

<p>I chose a template based on the popular <a href="https://ghost.org/blog/">ghost</a> platform called <a href="https://github.com/jekyller/jasper">Jasper</a>. There is another version called <a href="https://github.com/jekyller/jasper2">Jasper 2</a>, but I found the original Jasper version more my style.</p>

<p>The nice thing about choosing to use an open source template is that you are free to modify it to match your needs. This was not insurmountable in Wordpress, but much more challenging. I was also in fear of the template being upgraded that would make me have to figure out what changed, and if anything was broken.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>JS Equality Table</title>
	  <link>//2019-03-27-js-equality-table.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2019-03-27T15:25:39+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2019-03-27-js-equality-table.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>It seems I am always looking for the difference between <strong>==</strong> and <strong>===</strong>.  I was looking at a response to a question on Stackoverflow when I found this gem. I am publishing it here in case anyone else needs a graphical explanation.</p>

<p><a href="https://dorey.github.io/JavaScript-Equality-Table/">JavaScript-Equality-Table</a></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Wordpress</title>
	  <link>//2017-10-06-wordpress.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2017-10-06T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2017-10-06-wordpress.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I found Wordpress easier to use for my needs. The jekyll solution works for a lot of people, but I found that converting a Blogger blog to it was more difficult. If you are interested in my personal blog, please click on the links on the main page for my blogs.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>A new Blogging Platform with Github Pages</title>
	  <link>//2015-04-02-a-new-blog-site.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-04-02T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-04-02-a-new-blog-site.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I am looking at exporting my pages from Blogger to a platform where I can have more control over the layout. If this <em>endeavor</em>
works, I will look at moving my crown jewel from Blogger too.</p>

<p>I want to explore how difficult it is to get this setup and working effectively.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
