<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>johnyeary.com/</title>
   
   <link>https://johnyeary.com</link>
   <description>A Caffeinated Java Developer.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Joint Tactical Light Vehicle (JTLV)</title>
	  <link>//2015-09-05-joint-tactical-light-vehicle-jtlv.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-09-05T06:55:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-09-05-joint-tactical-light-vehicle-jtlv.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>The DoD awarded the the initial production run of the JTLV to <a href="http://oshkoshdefense1-px.rtrk.com">OshKosh Defense</a>. It seems to have produced a number of interesting remarks from outsiders who think OshKosh B’Gosh childrens clothing.</p>

<p>This is a fine weapon and delivery system and not a child’s toy. The image to the right I found using a Google search. I found it funny because of the tag on the front that says “No Photography”. The vehicle looks very nice, and hopefully will perform as expected.</p>

<p>The vehicle for me seems to have one visible flaw. The large undefended radiator grill in the front. I think that this needs to be covered more effectively, or moved to the top of the hood as much as possible.</p>

<p>The initial cost per unit is roughly $300K which is more than a HUMMV, but considerably lower than MRAP.</p>

<p>My expectation is that this vehicle helps protect our troops and bring them home safely at the end of the day. The price tag is not the defining issue here.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Military Lending Act Regulation Expansion</title>
	  <link>//2015-08-02-military-lending-act-regulation-expansion.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-02T10:46:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-08-02-military-lending-act-regulation-expansion.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I wanted to take a moment to thank the Obama Administration for their rule changes with regards to the Military Lending Act of 2006. The new regulations make it harder for lenders (let’s call them poachers) from charging outrageously high interest rates to our men and women who serve this country.</p>

<p>I still believe that Congress and this administration need to take a further step. The changes limit the cap on interest rates to 36%. This is still usury in its worst form. The Congress and administration should consider the cap at 20% for all citizens, but I would be happy if this considered this for military service members.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>First World War Officially Ends</title>
	  <link>//2010-09-30-first-world-war-officially-ends.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2010-09-30T19:26:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2010-09-30-first-world-war-officially-ends.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/1491px-Treaty_of_Versailles_Signing_Hall_of_Mirrors.jpg" alt="Signing of Treaty of Versailles" />
    <figcaption>Signing of Treaty of Versailles</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/World_War_I">First World
War</a>, “The war
to end all wars”, ended for most of us in 1919 at the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Treaty_of_Versailles">Treaty of
Versailles</a>.
After 92 years, it will end on Sunday. I love <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Military_history">military
history</a>,
but this one eluded me. The article in the <a href="http://www.telegraph.co.uk/news/worldnews/europe/germany/8029948/First-World-War-officially-ends.html">Telegraph:First World War
officially
ends</a>,
has more details, and it is an amazing story. Congratulations to Germany
for repaying their
<a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/War_reparations">war reparations</a>.
I appreciate their tenacity, and sense of responsibility. There are a
number of <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Allies">Allies</a> which
borrowed extensively from the U.S. during both wars that still have yet
to pay their debts back. Germany which had many reasons not to do it has
“done the right thing”.  Unfortunately this lesson in responsibility
will be lost on most Americans, especially the current generation.</p>

<p>Congrats Germany (Deutschland) on doing the right thing, and let us all
put the “War to end all wars” behind us, and look forward to the future.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
