<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>johnyeary.com/</title>
   
   <link>https://johnyeary.com</link>
   <description>A Caffeinated Java Developer.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Comprehensive Nuclear Test Ban Treaty (CTBT)</title>
	  <link>//2016-08-18-comprehensive-nuclear-test-ban-treaty-ctbt.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-18T21:19:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2016-08-18-comprehensive-nuclear-test-ban-treaty-ctbt.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>The Wall Street Journal had an article <a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/evading-the-constitution-to-ban-nuclear-tests-1471303498">Evading the Constitution to Ban Nuclear Tests</a> that discussed the Comprehensive Nuclear Test Ban Treaty (CTBT). The Obama administration is trying to make an end run around Congress to get the U.N. to make member states who are signatory and who have not ratified the treaty a party to it. Therefore making it illegal for the U.S. to test nuclear weapons.</p>

<p>I am shocked and appalled that a sitting U.S. President would put the American people, as well as, the free nations of the world at risk by attempting this maneuver. We have not tested any nuclear devices since 1992. We have used simulations to “test” our upgrades to the current weapon systems. The DOD has noted that this is reaching the end of its usefulness. The more we depart from the original designs, the more unpredictable our simulations become. The nuclear umbrella that keeps Russia and China, but more importantly these days N. Korea and Iran at bay is Mutually Assured Destruction (MUD). Our allies have lived under the security of this umbrella, and they have not had to keep stockpiles because of the safety we provide. This has made the world a safer place.</p>

<p>President Obama is attempting to usurp powers not given to him in the Constitution. The CTBT was rejected by the Senate in 1999 where sensible minds prevailed. Let me remind everyone that the original treaty was signed by President Bill Clinton whose wife is now running for the same office. I am not trying to make a political statement other than note that if they have the same beliefs; it will put us at risk again to ratifying a crippling treaty that only benefits our adversaries who do not play by the rules; think Iran and Russia to start.</p>

<p>Encourage your elected representatives, especially your Senators that this end run on the Constitution should be squarely put down, and reign in on Presidential power.</p>

<p>I swore an oath to uphold and defend the Constitution against all enemies foreign and <strong>domestic</strong>. This applies equally to elected officials that attempt to subvert their clearly defined powers.  Ask your Congressmen to do their jobs, and curb assumed Presidential powers.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Chinese Navy in US Territorial Waters</title>
	  <link>//2015-09-04-chinese-navy-in-us-territorial-waters.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-09-04T21:14:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-09-04-chinese-navy-in-us-territorial-waters.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>The Wall Street Journal reported yesterday and today that Chinese naval vessels were found in US territorial waters off of Alaska. Does this indicate a shift in Chinese military stance? I believe it is significant in its timing as noted in the articles.1, 2</p>

<p>There are five principle timing events to keep in mind: President Obama was visiting Alaska, the Chinese military was celebrating 70 years since the end of WWII  with an enormous parade (which coincidentally included Vladimir Putin as a guest), US military pivot to the Pacific, and US Naval challenge of the “freedom of the seas” in the Spratly Islands, and Chinese cyberwarfare against US government agencies and military.</p>

<p>The first seems to be a passive-aggressive issue where the Chinese are putting ships in an area where a US president is visiting. It is a technique we use to project force worldwide. Our typical stance is to send a carrier group to an area as a show of force. This seems on the surface to be the same thing. It is worth noting that while President Obama and Vladimir Putin were exchanging a phone conversation in July to celebrate Independence Day, the Russians sent bombers to Alaska and California. In both cases, I think we are expected to see the force projection.3</p>

<p>The Chinese sent invitations for the US to attend the 70th Anniversary of end of WWII celebrations which included an outlandish military parade 4, 5 reminiscent of Soviet military parades during the Cold War. The parade included the current militaristic dictator of Russia who I may conjecture knew of the Chinese vessels in Alaskan waters. Since previous to this event, they were engaged in military exercises with the Russians.</p>

<p>The US military pivot to the Pacific is old news, but it is significant in the Chinese eyes that they see the US as a threat to their agenda. One in which old adversaries of the US (Russia/China) play a strategic partnership to advance a thinly veiled expansion agenda.</p>

<p>The Chinese have been advancing their agenda in the South China Sea with the construction of artificial islands much to the chagrin of their neighbors. These islands include one which has a military air strip and radar installations. They have also threatened the US Navy with violations of their territorial waters, though in the case of the Spratly Islands in question, international law says otherwise. The tit-for-tat approach of the Chinese Navy in undisputed US territorial waters is a taunt to say “What is the US going to do about it?” The US military says that they are free to operate with the “freedom of the seas” carefully tossed back in our faces.</p>

<p>All of this occurs with the backdrop of the Chinese military spying on the US government and engaging in Cyber warfare. The Obama administration has emasculated the military and engaged in military bravado speeches about a pivot, and “freedom of the seas”.  The US Navy is in such a declined state, we can’t effectively project force, and we must “pivot”. Once upon a time, the US had a 600 ship navy second to none. Today, that navy is reduced to 236 commissioned ships and 417 if you count non-commissioned (USNS) and Ready Reserve Fleet. The 236 includes non-combatant vessels.6</p>

<p>If the US wants to continue to be a dominant military, this must change. The Russians and Chinese have figured out we are starting to soften, and are pushing in on the edges toward the center.</p>

<p>The only pivot I see here is at the waist of the military leaders who may also know it as <strong>BOHICA</strong>.</p>

<h3 id="references">References</h3>
<ol>
  <li>http://www.wsj.com/articles/pentagon-watches-as-chinese-navy-ships-sail-in-bering-sea-1441216258</li>
  <li>http://www.wsj.com/articles/chinese-navy-ships-off-alaska-passed-through-u-s-territorial-waters-1441350488</li>
  <li>http://www.cnn.com/2015/07/09/politics/russian-bombers-u-s-intercept-july-4/</li>
  <li>http://www.wsj.com/articles/china-flexes-its-military-muscle-at-world-war-ii-parade-1441282579</li>
  <li>http://www.wsj.com/articles/missing-from-beijings-military-spectacle-price-tag-1441210301</li>
  <li>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_current_ships_of_the_United_States_Navy</li>
</ol>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Op-ed: An S.O.S From Battleground Ukraine</title>
	  <link>//2015-08-02-op-ed-an-s-o-s-from-battleground-ukraine.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-02T18:14:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-08-02-op-ed-an-s-o-s-from-battleground-ukraine.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p><img src="data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAARMAAAC3CAMAAAAGjUrGAAAAD1BMVEUAW7v/1QAAVcCgnnX/2QA7hKVZAAAAzUlEQVR4nO3QsQGAMAzAsBT4/2b2eO0onaAZAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAAACASx62ednmY5vD5qSclJNyUk7KSTkpJ+WknJSTclJOykk5KSflpJyUk3JSTspJOSkn5aSclJNyUk7KSTkpJ+WknJSTclJOykk5KSflpJyUk3JSTspJOSkn5aSclJNyUk7KSTkpJ+WknJSTclJOykk5KSflpJyUk3JSTspJOSkn5aSclJNyUk7KSTkpJ+WknJSTclJOykk5KSflpH7zk2pa0LCuDAAAAABJRU5ErkJggg==" alt="" /></p>

<p>I finished reading the Opinion piece by Sohab Ahmari called <a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/message-from-battlefield-ukraine-1438106297">An S.O.S From Battleground Ukraine</a> and I too have been wondering why the US and NATO have turned their backs on Ukraine. Victor Poroshenko asked for 1,240 <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/FGM-148_Javelin">US Javelin anti-tank missiles</a>. As noted in the article, that is the exact number of nuclear warheads turned over by Ukraine in the 1994 Budapest Memorandum. If Ukraine had kept those nuclear missiles would we see the same level of aggression from Russia? Would Russia really have annexed Crimea? I am thinking they would have given pause to such aggressive behavior. The crystal ball is fuzzy on whether it would have stopped Czar Putin from his trophy, but it would likely have cost him more.</p>

<p>I am glad that the Ukrainian leadership in 1994 realized the issues around nuclear weapons, and surrendered them. The world is a safer place because of it, but <strong>Ukraine is not</strong> a safer place for it. I have friends and fellow Java leaders who live in Ukraine. I pray for their safety and well being. I just wish the US and NATO would come to their aid. Poking the Russian Bear is not only necessary, but warranted. Let’s make Czar Putin consider his calculus more carefully and reverse the direction of the “New Cold War”. By making Czar Putin’s life more miserable by mounting losses of manpower, and equipment like in Afghanistan, he may be forced to withdraw from Ukraine including Crimea, and leave South Ossetia to the Georgia</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Israeli Military Industries for Sale</title>
	  <link>//2015-08-02-israeli-military-industries-for-sale.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-02T13:45:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-08-02-israeli-military-industries-for-sale.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/Uzi_1-1-300x158.jpg" alt="Uzi 1" />
    <figcaption>Uzi 1</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Who made the famous Uzi?</p>

<p>You guessed it Israeli Military Industries (IMI). The iconic Uzi and its symbol of Israeli innovation and power is being sold. The Israeli Government is trying to divest itself of state-owned businesses. Perhaps having its leash cut, or at least lengthened may allow it to innovate and experience a new age of growth. Elbit Systems, Renco, and SK Group are in the bidding. Personally, I would like to see Elbit Systems, Ltd. win the bid. This would keep IMI part of the heritage of Israel, and keep weapons development in Israel.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Nuclear Deterrent</title>
	  <link>//2015-07-18-nuclear-deterrent.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-18T12:24:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-07-18-nuclear-deterrent.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>The article <a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/the-fading-u-s-nuclear-deterrent-1436739871">The Fading U.S. Nuclear
Deterrent</a>
in the Wall Street Journal by VADM Monroe should be an eye opener and
another wake-up call for the U.S policy makers. Admiral Monroe is in a
expert position to comment on the aging U.S. nuclear arsenal and forces.
Considering the long lead time for the upgrade of these forces, the time
is now to act. Our political and military leadership need to take the
steps necessary to begin the modernization process of our nuclear
forces.</p>

<p>Russia has recently made it known that they are proceeding with an
upgrade of their forces. China, Pakistan, India, North Korea are making
advances in their arsenals. North Korea is particularly troubling since
they are so unstable. They may not be able to hit Washington, but a
strike against California would be devastating.</p>

<p>I am not a fan of a number of President Obama’s policies, but the freeze
on the DoE National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA) R\&amp;D must
released. It was an critical failure on the part of the administration
of Mr. Obama to allow our nuclear forces to degrade.</p>

<p>This time in history like many that have preceded it has shown that the
good intentions of nations can not be relied on. “The war to end all
wars” ended in 1918, and only 21 years later began WW II. The United
Nations was founded in 1945 to promote peace and unity among member
nations. This was followed by the Cold War that lasted until 1991. This
is not the time to turn our warheads into fuel rods. This is the time to
ensure that we can negotiate with our potential adversaries on high
ground.</p>

<p>Contact your elected representatives and let them know you want them to
support our military forces with modern equipment, and programs.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Cyber Warfare</title>
	  <link>//2015-07-18-cyber-warfare.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-07-18T11:09:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-07-18-cyber-warfare.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>In the Opinion section of the Wall Street Journal for Monday, 13 July
2015, there was an article posted by L. Gordon Crovitz entitled <a href="http://www.wsj.com/articles/portents-of-world-cyberwar-1436740393">Portents of World
Cyberwar</a>.
The article is a short and well done read about a possible future
conflict.</p>

<p>The fictional opposition is China in a book called “Ghost Fleet” in the article. However, the reality is that China and Russia are two of our current adversaries. The Chinese and Russians have been identified in some very high profile cyber attacks recently.</p>

<p>The Russians are currently sanctioned by the US and EU for its activities in Ukraine. The “war” is already on. The Russians have even flown bombers directly off the coast of Alaska and more alarmingly California on the 4th of July. This while Putin was calling President Obama to extend a “warm” message.</p>

<p>The Chinese are currently building air strips and military bases on coral islands in a multilateral disputed territory in the South China Sea. The US has already threatened overflights, and naval vessels passing within the 12 nautical miles of the islands.</p>

<p>The Chinese has successfully infiltrated into some of our most secure data. The direct damage and collateral damage will shortly become more apparent. Since we don’t know the names of the disclosed foreign contacts as the American public, we will never really be sure of who is caught in the web. The NSA, FBI, and CIA will need to make a concerted effort to keep track of these individuals to see if the Chinese government detains, imprisons, or worse. The collateral damage could be providing that information to foreign governments in an effort to secure favor. We know that the Chinese military-industrial complex is largely state-owned. As a result, it can be expected that it can use that intelligence to its benefit.</p>

<p>In a number of countries, political leaders would be placed in a bad position with their citizens if the extent of their involvement with our government. The Chinese could easily use this information to discredit, or blackmail these leaders for favors.</p>

<p>The article mentions the Chinese activities with regards to stealing information on the F-35 in 2009. The technical data can be used to develop weapons to detect and destroy these aircraft. It also provides the Chinese with R&amp;D for free. American technology will be used to develop the next generation of Chinese fighter aircraft.</p>

<p>The reality is that these sophisticated weapons systems require lots of electronics. The majority of these electronics come from China, Taiwan, Korea, and Japan. The latter three countries are within striking distance of China in its current military state. This would deprive the US of vital materials needed in a war. The possibility of making fab-labs in the US in a timely manner is not realistic. It takes a significant amount of time and experienced personnel. The reality is that those experienced personnel are largely in the countries noted. Another sobering issue is that the equipment to build these fab-labs are also largely made in those countries. This represents an Achilles heel to our national security objectives. This is expected to be further exacerbated by companies like Intel building more facilities overseas.</p>

<p>Is the fantasy about crippling code built into the chips really that much of a stretch? May I remind the reader that is exactly what some intelligence agency did to the Iranians to damage their Uranium enrichment centrifuges. The code caused the machinery to operate in a degraded manner, or fail. So is it possible to send a triggering command to shut off the electronics on an F-35? The flight controls are fly-by-wire. So, it is even possible to crash them into the Earth without a shot being fired. Do you think that is fantasy? A recent Black Hat conference demonstrated how to hack the systems in your automobile.</p>

<p>The opening salvo has been fired. What will be our response? Measured?</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Linda Norgrove's Tragic Death</title>
	  <link>//2010-10-12-linda-norgroves-tragic-death.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2010-10-12T12:23:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2010-10-12-linda-norgroves-tragic-death.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="https://civiliancontractors.files.wordpress.com/2011/02/linda-norgrove-grid-6x2.jpg" alt="Linda Norgrove" />
    <figcaption>Linda Norgrove</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Let me start by extending my deepest condolences to Ms Norgrove’s family. The work your daughter was doing to help the lives of those less fortunate is commendable. On behalf of all those who support those who help others, this loss is even more tragic.</p>

<p>I support an inquiry into the events of Ms. Norgrove’s death, but I am disheartened that their seems to be a bunch of finger pointing at the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Special_Forces_%28United_States_Army%29">American Special Forces</a> team that were attempting her rescue. The fact that Linda was kidnapped and being held against her will seems to be lost here. Also the fact that the commanders on the ground believed her to be in imminent danger seems to be overlooked.</p>

<p>I know that if I were Linda, I would have liked for someone to rescue me. I am sure she would understand that there was no malice, and that the brave team that went in to rescue her at their peril were trying to do the right thing.</p>

<p>I want to take a moment to say thank you to the troops who risked their lives to save her, and take with them a lessons learned. Hold your heads up high and don’t let this tragedy distract you from your mission.</p>

<p>Today, tomorrow, or next week you may be asked to go into harms way again to attempt a rescue of someone else, and that needs to be your focus.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Transportation Workers Identification Card (TWIC)</title>
	  <link>//2010-04-02-transportation-workers-identification-card-twic.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2010-04-02T23:43:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2010-04-02-transportation-workers-identification-card-twic.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>All maritime personnel are now required to get a TWIC card before they can get their Merchant Mariners Document (MMD) issued. The TWIC is issued by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA).</p>

<p>I found the process easy, but in some ways a silly bureaucratic quagmire. The form states that answering “YES” to the following questions will automatically disqualify you. Then they ask essentially if you are a terrorist. OK… If you were a terrorist would you answer “YES”. If you did, well you are the worst damn terrorist in the world and deserve to be laughed to death in prison.</p>

<p>Anyway, they ask additional questions about felonies and convictions, etc. Some of items were not necessarily disqualifying. As I sat in the TSA waiting room for my turn to be photographed and finger printed, I looked around the room. I wondered how many of the people in the room answered “YES” to those questions. I know I shouldn’t judge a book by its cover, but there were some folks with some prison tattoos sitting in there with me.</p>

<p>My real question for the TSA is why ask someone about felonies, etc. when you are going to do a National Agency Check (NAC) anyway. The criminal backgrounds would be apparent anyway. Are you doing a test to see if a felon would knowingly admit to being a felon, and if not you could throw him back in jail for falsifying his application?</p>

<p>I can understand asking those questions of a foreign national who may be applying since those national records may not be available to US agencies. Americans though? Perhaps you should streamline the process and ask them to declare any convictions in countries other that the US.</p>

<p>Anyway, I am a clean, coca-cola, baseball, mom’s apple pie, all American patriot so I had no issues getting a TWIC. Step one of getting my new MMD is complete.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Censorship in Asia</title>
	  <link>//2009-09-14-censorship-in-asia.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-09-14T20:29:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-09-14-censorship-in-asia.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I read a very good article this morning on the growing censorship of the Internet and blogging in Asia. The article: <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB125288982580207609.html" title="Wall Street Journal Article - Web Censoring Widens Across Southeast Asia">Web Censoring Widens Across Southeast Asia</a> was published in the Wall Street Journal for Monday, 14 September 2009.</p>

<p>The article details a number of efforts by governments to systematically stymie opposition groups, political dissenters, or individual bloggers. I am alarmed that the government in Malaysia would invoke a colonial era Internal Security Act to detain individuals for two years without trial.</p>

<p>The government is trying to put on a friendly moderate face to encourage western companies, and investors to help develop their growing economy. The problem is that laws like the Internal Security Act undermine this moderate view of Malaysia.</p>

<p>The article indicates that 63% of people in Malaysia use the Internet. This is incredible and really provides an opportunity for the government to engage their people.</p>

<p>I am not trying to single out Malaysia by any means, but the closest county in Internet users in the article is Iran with 32%. I don’t see them making any changes to become more open soon.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Decisive Force in Afganistan</title>
	  <link>//2009-09-14-decisive-force-in-afganistan.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-09-14T20:22:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-09-14-decisive-force-in-afganistan.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I read the op-ed piece in the Wall Street Journal by Lindsey Graham,
Joesph Lieberman, and John McCain today called <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424052970203440104574404753110979442.html" title="Wall Street Journal Article - Only Decisive Force Can Prevail in Afghanistan">Only Decisive Force Can
Prevail in
Afghanistan</a>.
I respect Messrs. Graham and McCain for their service to this great
country, but on this opinion piece I am not sure I can agree completely.</p>

<p>As military officers they understand the requirements of a successful
military engagement, but in country building they are far less experts.
There has been a ratcheting up of rhetoric around pushing more troops
there, but to what avail. Even if we crush the current Taliban forces,
the rear guard can be repopulated from the poor and starving masses. A
military push can not be successful unless it also brings a significant
civilian component along.</p>

<p>Idle hands and minds in the hinterland form
the foundation of the Taliban. Unless we can find a better solutions to
the idleness and abject poverty, we will continue to engage the same
enemy in perpetuity. We need a cadre of well trained people to engage
the local population. This includes experts on farming, and animal
husbandry. It is harder to convince someone to die when they have hope
for a better future.</p>

<p><strong>How can you help?</strong></p>

<p>Tell your Congressman you
want humanitarian assistance to accompany those troops.  You can also
help with providing micro-loans to young entrepreneurs in Afghanistan
with  programs like
<a href="http://www.kiva.org/" title="Kiva - Loans that change lives.">Kiva</a> and
<a href="http://www.grameenfoundation.org/" title="Grameen Foundation">Grameen
Foundation</a></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
