<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>johnyeary.com/</title>
   
   <link>https://johnyeary.com</link>
   <description>A Caffeinated Java Developer.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Resolutions</title>
	  <link>//2020-01-01-resolution.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2020-01-01-resolution.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h1 id="do-achievable-things">Do Achievable Things!</h1>

<p>Every year most people make resolutions to do things like lose weight, eat more at home, travel, etc. After
some period of time most of those resolutions follow the way of the dinosaur. This year my New Year’s resolution
is to <strong>Do Achievable Things</strong>. This phrase is meant to act as a reminder to make decisions to do things that you can feel
a sense of success. Pick small tasks like walk daily, or run a mile. These small acts add up over time and builds upon success after success.</p>

<p>This last year I lost 30 lbs. I was running everyday, and switched over to a training plan to run a half-marathon this month. Unfortunately, I got a really bad
cold with bronchitis which totally derailed my running and training. The goal was reachable, but forces outside my control are going to make this goal unreachable
this month. Once I am back to being healthy, I will achieve this goal.</p>

<p>One of the goals I have is to migrate my blog from Wordpress over to Github, and to write more frequently. Let’s see how that works out by the end of 2020.</p>

<p>Happy New Year 2020.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Patriotism</title>
	  <link>//2018-07-04-patriotism.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-07-04T13:48:50+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2018-07-04-patriotism.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3 id="independence-day">Independence Day…</h3>

<p>I think most Americans will celebrate with food, fireworks, and perhaps some beverages (adult or otherwise. The historical context is lost to many.</p>

<p>Beer and barbecues have made this a classic for summer. Most families plan holidays around this date and it has become one less day of vacation charged against them for the year.</p>

<p>Let me tell you a little story of Dave and Goliath. On July 2nd, 1776, a group of what we would later call “Patriots” decided to declare independence from Great Britain. Two days later, the rebellion was on. The delegates from the 13 colonies signed the Declaration of Independence. Thirteen colonies against “The Empire”; like I said David vs. Goliath.</p>

<p>Fortunately for a number of events at the time, and the distance of the colonies from Britain, our fledgling rebellion had a chance. Today we know that was more than a mere chance, but to our Founding Fathers it was as likely to fail as succeed. Failure they understood would have them hanging from trees and gallows across the colonies. It meant that their families would be punished, and their fortunes ruined. This was a huge risk.</p>

<h3 id="the-birth-of-a-nation">The Birth of a Nation</h3>

<p>Fortunately, our Founding Fathers had a number of things going for them that made them more than just rebellious traitors. They were on the whole very bright, well educated, thoughtful, introspective, and surprisingly forward thinking. These men, who form a well known circle in American thinking, were Thomas Jefferson, John Adams, and Benjamin Franklin. Thomas Jefferson being the primary author of the Declaration of Independence is considered with a special regards.</p>

<p>The preceding conflicts in 1775 and subsequent American Revolution made The Declaration of Independence more than just ink on paper; it cost real lives. It was really America’s first civil war. Remember we were all citizens of the crown. There were friends and family on both sides of this conflict just as in the later Civil War.</p>

<p>Success and luck on the battlefield with the assistance of the French turned the paper tiger of ink to the reality we have today.</p>

<p>Let me ask you a question for your own reflection. Would you be willing to sacrifice your life, and more importantly that of your families for an idea? An untested, and unproven idea to say the least.</p>

<h3 id="what-does-it-mean-to-be-patriotic">What does it mean to be patriotic?</h3>

<p>It means believing in the rule of law. It means that if you don’t like the laws: change them. There is a place for civil disobedience, but in the context of a legal framework.</p>

<p>It means exercising your right to vote. If you don’t vote, you have disenfranchised yourself. You can complain about your politicians, it is your right to do so. However if you didn’t vote, you are responsible for your own fate.</p>

<p>It means challenging your government. We have become complacent in accepting double speak from our elected officials. Why do politicians need spokespeople? Shouldn’t they be able to tell you what they think? You should hold them suspect for having public relations and spokespeople. It means they are interested in public perception and not public action.</p>

<p>We honor our soldiers and sailors. We should. However, uniformed members of Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) should be deserving of our respect as well. They are trying to do their jobs in a volatile and heated political environment. The majority of them, like members of our uniformed services, are good and decent people with very difficult jobs. Don’t deride a person’s job if you wouldn’t be willing to do it yourself. <strong>Think garbage man</strong>.</p>

<p>It means standing for our flag even if you are angry with your government. It is a symbol of <strong>YOUR</strong> freedom and an ideal that many people before and after you will make the ultimate sacrifice to ensure.</p>

<p>It is <strong>OUR</strong> Constitution that gives you rights. Consider it on the basis of Life, Liberty, and the Pursuit of Happiness, and keep it close to your buxom. Read it yourself.</p>

<p>I am sure many of you can offer your own suggestions of what it means to be patriotic.</p>

<h3 id="historical-interest">Historical Interest</h3>

<ul>
  <li>John Adams told his wife Abigail that July 2nd would be celebrated as the day of independence. He refused to accept the 4th as the date, and would not celebrate it.</li>
  <li>Thomas Jefferson and John Adams died on July 4th 1826. Fifty years to the date of the signing of The Declaration of Independence.</li>
  <li>The first celebrations were mock funerals of King George III.</li>
  <li>It became a Federal Holiday in 1870. Seventy-One years later, it became a paid holiday for Federal employees in 1941. This was just before our entrance into another war in which we were Allies with our former colonial rulers.</li>
  <li>At the end of the American Revolution, there were two primary political parties: Federalist and humorously today: Democratic-Republicans. We could only hope for such a middle of the isle centrist ruling coalition today.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h3>

<p>On the 4th, when you are enjoying your overcooked hotdog, hoist up your sun burned hand, and toast a cold beer to these brave citizens that gave you the freedom you have today.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Disabling and Enabling Hyper-V on Windows</title>
	  <link>//2018-05-18-disabling-and-enabling-hyper-v-on-windows.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-05-18T03:20:22+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2018-05-18-disabling-and-enabling-hyper-v-on-windows.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I needed to be able to run VMWare and VirtualBox from my Windows 10 Pro machine. This machine also has Docker on it. The issue is that you can only have one Hypervisor working at a time. So Docker <strong>OR</strong> VirtualBox and VMWare. A temporary solution is to disable the Hyper-V using the following commands. Once this disabled, you can run VirtualBox and VMWare.</p>

<h3 id="disable">Disable</h3>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>bcdedit /set hypervisorlaunchtype off
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Reboot machine.</p>

<h3 id="enable">Enable</h3>
<div class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge"><div class="highlight"><pre class="highlight"><code>bcdedit /set hypervisorlaunchtype auto
</code></pre></div></div>
<p>Reboot machine.</p>

<h3 id="long-term-solution">Long Term Solution</h3>

<p>A long-term solution using alternate boot commands is what I ended up using. The details can be found in this article: <a href="https://nickjanetakis.com/blog/docker-tip-13-get-docker-for-windows-and-virtualbox-working-together">Docker Tip #13: Get Docker for Windows and VirtualBox Working Together</a>.</p>

<p>This is for someone like me who switches more frequently than a casual user.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>American Horror Story - Cult</title>
	  <link>//2017-09-07-american-horror-story-cult.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2017-09-07T02:03:55+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2017-09-07-american-horror-story-cult.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I know it is in its 7th season, but I watched the first episode of season 7 tonight on FX. I was not scared, but I will say that it was creepy if not predictable in a horrible way. I will tune in next week to watch the second episode in the series. I really don’t want to give anything away.</p>

<p>I personally was satisfied to skip social media before watching it so I would be surprised. Yes, it was creepy and I dare say more scary that it almost seemed realistic.</p>

<p>I did not need to suspend disbelief to see this happening today. A sad commentary on society in general, but makes for a good series.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>GMO Golden Rice 3 and Solving Worldwide Malnutrition</title>
	  <link>//2017-08-13-gmo-golden-rice-3-and-solving-worldwide-malnutrition.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2017-08-13T21:46:05+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2017-08-13-gmo-golden-rice-3-and-solving-worldwide-malnutrition.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I just finished reading an article called New ‘golden rice’ offers 3 micronutrients1 which would go a long way to solving malnutrition in a significant portion of the world. The article mentions that about 50% of the world uses rice as their primary means of nutrition.</p>

<p>The natural varieties of rice don’t provide Iron, Zinc, or Vitamin A which are sources of various diseases that are not normally encountered in western countries. The new GMO rice has Iron, Zinc, and Beta-Carotene ( Vitamin A precursor). This is a fantastic accomplishment. I can see this helping to solve world hunger and malnutrition needs. However, it is GMO, and releasing GMO foods into nature are presenting issues in the developed world.</p>

<p>One needs only to look at farmers in the US who are having their crops destroyed by weed-killer that does not affect GMO modified varieties that are modified to be tolerant. A recent example is soybeans in the Southern US2. There are also the question of whether GMO crops can resist some diseases that the natural varieties can, as well as,  survive in their native climates (don’t plant a palm tree in the desert and cacti in a rain forest)3.</p>

<p>Balance, I know that we must find a balance between third-world issues like malnutrition, and first world issues like GMO crops. However, I think we as responsible citizens need to pay more attention and oversight into the release of these modified species into the wild. We can’t put the djinni back in the bottle once it has been released. I want to solve the malnutrition, and hunger issues, but not at the future peril of all food crops.</p>

<h3 id="references">References</h3>
<ul>
  <li><a href="http://www.futurity.org/golden-rice-nutrients-1508082/">New ‘golden rice’ offers 3 micronutrients</a>.</li>
  <li><a href="http://www.motherjones.com/food/2017/06/farmers-say-this-weedkiller-is-also-killing-their-soybean-plants/">Farmers Say This Weedkiller Is Also Killing Their Soybean Plants</a></li>
  <li><a href="https://www.scientificamerican.com/article/farmers-say-gmo-corn-no-longer-resistant-to-pests/">Farmers Say GMO Corn No Longer Resistant to Pests</a></li>
</ul>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Free LED Bulbs from Duke Energy</title>
	  <link>//2017-08-13-free-led-bulbs-from-duke-energy.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2017-08-13T00:16:49+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2017-08-13-free-led-bulbs-from-duke-energy.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="https://storage.googleapis.com/methodical-kaleidoscope-7367/2017/08/LEDBulbs-201x300.jpg" alt="Free LED Bulbs" />
    <figcaption>Free LED Bulbs</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I received an 8-pack of “Simply Conserve 9W / 60W LED Warm White (2700K) Light Bulbs” yesterday from Duke Energy. Today, I installed all of them, and moved some CFL bulbs around to less used lights in the house. The goal will be to use all LED lights in the house. This is a good start.</p>

<p>I had an opportunity to send remarks to Duke Energy and take a survey on their program. I am very pleased to see that Duke Energy is trying to help customers become more energy efficient. It helps lower their costs, our costs, and more importantly drives us towards a greener future.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>World Vision and Hamas</title>
	  <link>//2016-08-18-world-vision-and-hamas.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-08-18T23:12:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2016-08-18-world-vision-and-hamas.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="https://storage.googleapis.com/methodical-kaleidoscope-7367/2016/08/worldvision.png" alt="World Vision" />
    <figcaption>World Vision</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I am following the legal proceedings against Mohammad El-Halabi. Over the years, my family has contributed to World Vision. Discovering that there is a possibility that the money was funnelled to a terrorist organization bent on the destruction of Israel, and violation of my Christian principles is troubling to say the least.</p>

<p>Israeli prosecutors allege $7.2 million a year was being transferred for over 5 years.  If this is true, then I feel betrayed by World Vision and its accounting failures. It would also mean that we have been fueling the ongoing crisis in Israel, Gaza Strip, Lebanon, and Syria. It also means that those funds which were slated to do “good works” have been siphoned off to do evil in the world.</p>

<p>World Vision, and other Christian NGOs should heed this siren call, and keep a better eye on their books. Otherwise funding from Christians like myself will dry up and disappear.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>My son is trying his hand at Blogging</title>
	  <link>//2016-06-29-my-son-is-trying-his-hand-at-blogging.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2016-06-29T21:26:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2016-06-29-my-son-is-trying-his-hand-at-blogging.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="https://storage.googleapis.com/methodical-kaleidoscope-7367/2017/08/LastDayMonarchElementary.jpg" alt="Sean Yeary - Last day of school at Monarch (5th Grade)" />
    <figcaption>Sean Yeary - Last day of school at Monarch (5th Grade)</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The WWW needs to be on the lookout for my youngest son. He is trying his hand at blogging. <a href="http://thepolarbearboy.blogspot.com/">The Polar Bear Boy</a> is on the loose.</p>

<p>He is a huge fan of video games so expect some great content if you are into Destiny and Fallout 4.</p>

<p>He is also a master Minecrafter.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Huawei - Ballet Slippers</title>
	  <link>//2015-08-02-huawei-ballet-slippers.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-02T14:56:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-08-02-huawei-ballet-slippers.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>This advertisement caused a lot of controversy about the apparent distastefulness of the photo. <strong>I strongly disagree!</strong> The image is a great example of the hard work that it takes to make a ballet performance seem effortless.</p>

<p>Anything worth doing requires hard work and perseverance.  I love this image. I think it serves to show people the true cost of perfection.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Legos without Plastics?</title>
	  <link>//2015-08-02-legos-without-plastics.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2015-08-02T13:33:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2015-08-02-legos-without-plastics.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I see that Lego is trying to develop a new material replacement for the iconic ABS plastic blocks it uses in its products. They used 77,000 metric tonnes of petroleum based ABS plastic to manufacture 60 million bricks in 2014. Apparently the challenge is to use a replacement material that will have the same color and characteristics as existing bricks. This will be no small challenge. I applaud their efforts, and I hope they are successful.</p>

<p>However, I am not sure if that is as important as reducing the reliance on ABS plastic. Fruity Pebbles went all natural and removed the artificial colors. Yes, the colors are more natural and muted, but I like them better than radioactive yellow and magenta and biohazard red anyway. Perhaps they can make some corn stalk all natural blocks and test the market waters. I imagine today they would be well received.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
