<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>johnyeary.com/</title>
   
   <link>https://johnyeary.com</link>
   <description>A Caffeinated Java Developer.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Resolutions</title>
	  <link>//2020-01-01-resolution.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2020-01-01-resolution.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h1 id="do-achievable-things">Do Achievable Things!</h1>

<p>Every year most people make resolutions to do things like lose weight, eat more at home, travel, etc. After
some period of time most of those resolutions follow the way of the dinosaur. This year my New Year’s resolution
is to <strong>Do Achievable Things</strong>. This phrase is meant to act as a reminder to make decisions to do things that you can feel
a sense of success. Pick small tasks like walk daily, or run a mile. These small acts add up over time and builds upon success after success.</p>

<p>This last year I lost 30 lbs. I was running everyday, and switched over to a training plan to run a half-marathon this month. Unfortunately, I got a really bad
cold with bronchitis which totally derailed my running and training. The goal was reachable, but forces outside my control are going to make this goal unreachable
this month. Once I am back to being healthy, I will achieve this goal.</p>

<p>One of the goals I have is to migrate my blog from Wordpress over to Github, and to write more frequently. Let’s see how that works out by the end of 2020.</p>

<p>Happy New Year 2020.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Patriotism</title>
	  <link>//2018-07-04-patriotism.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2018-07-04T13:48:50+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2018-07-04-patriotism.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h3 id="independence-day">Independence Day…</h3>

<p>I think most Americans will celebrate with food, fireworks, and perhaps some beverages (adult or otherwise. The historical context is lost to many.</p>

<p>Beer and barbecues have made this a classic for summer. Most families plan holidays around this date and it has become one less day of vacation charged against them for the year.</p>

<p>Let me tell you a little story of Dave and Goliath. On July 2nd, 1776, a group of what we would later call “Patriots” decided to declare independence from Great Britain. Two days later, the rebellion was on. The delegates from the 13 colonies signed the Declaration of Independence. Thirteen colonies against “The Empire”; like I said David vs. Goliath.</p>

<p>Fortunately for a number of events at the time, and the distance of the colonies from Britain, our fledgling rebellion had a chance. Today we know that was more than a mere chance, but to our Founding Fathers it was as likely to fail as succeed. Failure they understood would have them hanging from trees and gallows across the colonies. It meant that their families would be punished, and their fortunes ruined. This was a huge risk.</p>

<h3 id="the-birth-of-a-nation">The Birth of a Nation</h3>

<p>Fortunately, our Founding Fathers had a number of things going for them that made them more than just rebellious traitors. They were on the whole very bright, well educated, thoughtful, introspective, and surprisingly forward thinking. These men, who form a well known circle in American thinking, were Thomas Jefferson, John Adams, and Benjamin Franklin. Thomas Jefferson being the primary author of the Declaration of Independence is considered with a special regards.</p>

<p>The preceding conflicts in 1775 and subsequent American Revolution made The Declaration of Independence more than just ink on paper; it cost real lives. It was really America’s first civil war. Remember we were all citizens of the crown. There were friends and family on both sides of this conflict just as in the later Civil War.</p>

<p>Success and luck on the battlefield with the assistance of the French turned the paper tiger of ink to the reality we have today.</p>

<p>Let me ask you a question for your own reflection. Would you be willing to sacrifice your life, and more importantly that of your families for an idea? An untested, and unproven idea to say the least.</p>

<h3 id="what-does-it-mean-to-be-patriotic">What does it mean to be patriotic?</h3>

<p>It means believing in the rule of law. It means that if you don’t like the laws: change them. There is a place for civil disobedience, but in the context of a legal framework.</p>

<p>It means exercising your right to vote. If you don’t vote, you have disenfranchised yourself. You can complain about your politicians, it is your right to do so. However if you didn’t vote, you are responsible for your own fate.</p>

<p>It means challenging your government. We have become complacent in accepting double speak from our elected officials. Why do politicians need spokespeople? Shouldn’t they be able to tell you what they think? You should hold them suspect for having public relations and spokespeople. It means they are interested in public perception and not public action.</p>

<p>We honor our soldiers and sailors. We should. However, uniformed members of Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) should be deserving of our respect as well. They are trying to do their jobs in a volatile and heated political environment. The majority of them, like members of our uniformed services, are good and decent people with very difficult jobs. Don’t deride a person’s job if you wouldn’t be willing to do it yourself. <strong>Think garbage man</strong>.</p>

<p>It means standing for our flag even if you are angry with your government. It is a symbol of <strong>YOUR</strong> freedom and an ideal that many people before and after you will make the ultimate sacrifice to ensure.</p>

<p>It is <strong>OUR</strong> Constitution that gives you rights. Consider it on the basis of Life, Liberty, and the Pursuit of Happiness, and keep it close to your buxom. Read it yourself.</p>

<p>I am sure many of you can offer your own suggestions of what it means to be patriotic.</p>

<h3 id="historical-interest">Historical Interest</h3>

<ul>
  <li>John Adams told his wife Abigail that July 2nd would be celebrated as the day of independence. He refused to accept the 4th as the date, and would not celebrate it.</li>
  <li>Thomas Jefferson and John Adams died on July 4th 1826. Fifty years to the date of the signing of The Declaration of Independence.</li>
  <li>The first celebrations were mock funerals of King George III.</li>
  <li>It became a Federal Holiday in 1870. Seventy-One years later, it became a paid holiday for Federal employees in 1941. This was just before our entrance into another war in which we were Allies with our former colonial rulers.</li>
  <li>At the end of the American Revolution, there were two primary political parties: Federalist and humorously today: Democratic-Republicans. We could only hope for such a middle of the isle centrist ruling coalition today.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="final-thoughts">Final Thoughts</h3>

<p>On the 4th, when you are enjoying your overcooked hotdog, hoist up your sun burned hand, and toast a cold beer to these brave citizens that gave you the freedom you have today.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Pulled Pork</title>
	  <link>//2011-07-10-pulled-pork.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2011-07-10T12:34:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2011-07-10-pulled-pork.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/HomemadePulledPork.jpg" alt="Pulled Pork" />
    <figcaption>Pulled Pork</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The other day my wife made pulled pork. She cooked it in a slow cooker all day.</p>

<p>When I went to cut it up and pull it apart, I did it mostly by hand. It truly was hand pulled pork. It simply melted in your mouth it was so tender.</p>

<p><strong>Delicious!</strong></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Kudzu Blossom Jelly</title>
	  <link>//2011-07-10-kudzu-blossom-jelly.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2011-07-10T10:57:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2011-07-10-kudzu-blossom-jelly.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/KudzuBlossomJelly.jpg" alt="Kudzu Blossom Jelly" />
    <figcaption>Kudzu Blossom Jelly</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>In my last post on <a href="/2011-07-10-moonshine-jelly.html">Moonshine Jelly</a>. I mentioned a neat general store where you can get some unusual food. While I was there, I purchased some Kudzu Blossom Jelly.</p>

<p>For those of you who may not know, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kudzu">Kudzu</a> is a vine which is native to Japan. It was introduced in the Southern United States in a variety of ways. The largest introduction was from the Soil Conservation Service. It is now considered a week, and responsible for enormous habitat destruction in the Southeastern United States.</p>

<p>Kudzu Blossom Jelly seems to be at least some practical use for it. This jelly is a surprisingly sweet jelly with a nice “wild” taste. I would recommend eating as much as you like and help save the South.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Moonshine Jelly</title>
	  <link>//2011-07-10-moonshine-jelly.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2011-07-10T10:43:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2011-07-10-moonshine-jelly.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/MoonshineJelly.jpg" alt="Moonshine Jelly" />
    <figcaption>Moonshine Jelly</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>There are few things that I must say are quite entertaining about living
in South Carolina. I went into a restaurant/general store in
<a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=Pumpkintown,+SC&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=35.002898,-82.653065&amp;spn=0.033044,0.066047&amp;sll=35.047681,-82.624001&amp;sspn=0.002075,0.004128&amp;z=15">Pumpkintown,
SC</a>.
Yes “Pumpkintown”! The general store called <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=35.048048,-82.62418&amp;ll=35.047681,-82.624001&amp;spn=0.002075,0.004128&amp;sll=35.00278,-82.65306&amp;sspn=0.018281,0.032015&amp;num=1&amp;t=h&amp;z=19&amp;iwloc=lyrftr:h,11835591884208069584,35.047754,-82.623799">Pumpkintown
Mountain</a>
at the Pumpkintown Opera. They have an unusual assortment of foods
including Moonshine Jelly. I could not pass on such an opportunity to
try such a treat.</p>

<figure class="image">
    <img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-l8swJm9fjU0/Thm58-VKMNI/AAAAAAAABP4/qRqvAMpU3Pw/s1600/ToastCoffeeMoonshineJelly.jpg" alt="Moonshine Jelly, Toast, and Coffee" />
    <figcaption>Moonshine Jelly, Toast, and Coffee</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I don’t know what I was expecting. I thought it might taste like alcohol, or have a sharp taste. Actually, it has a sweet taste with a pleasant “moonshine” taste. I would recommend trying some if you get a chance. You will not be disappointed, and may even feel like you are getting away with something from them “Revenue agents”.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Beautiful Butterflies at Table Rock State Park</title>
	  <link>//2011-06-13-beautiful-butterflies-at-table-rock-state-park.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2011-06-13T16:20:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2011-06-13-beautiful-butterflies-at-table-rock-state-park.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/IMG_0201.jpg" alt="Beautiful Butterflies at Table Rock State Park" />
    <figcaption>Beautiful Butterflies at Table Rock State Park</figcaption>
</figure>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>HP50g Graphing Calculator</title>
	  <link>//2010-05-04-hp50g-graphing-calculator.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2010-05-04T08:51:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2010-05-04-hp50g-graphing-calculator.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>My new HP50g calculator arrived. I am really impressed with it. The functionality is incredible. There are a number of manuals and tutorials which come with the calculator. I completed the first manual, but I can tell that I have a long way to go with the tutorials.</p>

<p>If you are an engineer, scientist, or mathematician looking for a great calculator; the HP50g should be on your short list.</p>

<iframe style="width:120px;height:240px;" marginwidth="0" marginheight="0" scrolling="no" frameborder="0" src="//ws-na.amazon-adsystem.com/widgets/q?ServiceVersion=20070822&amp;OneJS=1&amp;Operation=GetAdHtml&amp;MarketPlace=US&amp;source=ac&amp;ref=qf_sp_asin_til&amp;ad_type=product_link&amp;tracking_id=johnyeary.com-20&amp;marketplace=amazon&amp;region=US&amp;placement=B000GTPRPS&amp;asins=B000GTPRPS&amp;linkId=75fc6b2c873b6d5598447138d78646cf&amp;show_border=true&amp;link_opens_in_new_window=true&amp;price_color=333333&amp;title_color=0066c0&amp;bg_color=ffffff">
</iframe>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Dead Calculator</title>
	  <link>//2010-04-25-dead-calculator.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2010-04-25T17:23:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2010-04-25-dead-calculator.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I was really bummed. I thought that the batteries in my TI-85 calculator were finally dying so I bought new ones yesterday. Well it turns out that the screen is dying a quick pixel death. I have had it since college. I bought it in 1992, and it will finally be retired when my new calculator arrives.</p>

<p>So I spent a couple of hours researching calculators this afternoon. I finally decided to purchase an HP 50g graphing calculator.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Volume of a Pizza</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-16-volume-of-a-pizza.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-16T10:58:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-16-volume-of-a-pizza.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <script src="https://cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML" type="text/javascript"></script>

<p>The general equation for the volume of a cylindrical object is noted by
the following equation.</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">v = \pi r^2h</script>

<p><img src="/assets/images/volume.gif" alt="" /></p>

<p>If a pizza has a radius of <strong>z</strong> and a height of <strong>a</strong>, then the volume
of a pizza can be determined by the following equation:</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">p_v = pi * z * z * a</script>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Reflections</title>
	  <link>//2009-09-14-reflections.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-09-14T20:38:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-09-14-reflections.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/IMG_0023.jpg" alt="Reflections" />
    <figcaption>Reflections</figcaption>
</figure>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
