<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>johnyeary.com/</title>
   
   <link>https://johnyeary.com</link>
   <description>A Caffeinated Java Developer.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Resolutions</title>
	  <link>//2020-01-01-resolution.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2020-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2020-01-01-resolution.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <h1 id="do-achievable-things">Do Achievable Things!</h1>

<p>Every year most people make resolutions to do things like lose weight, eat more at home, travel, etc. After
some period of time most of those resolutions follow the way of the dinosaur. This year my New Year’s resolution
is to <strong>Do Achievable Things</strong>. This phrase is meant to act as a reminder to make decisions to do things that you can feel
a sense of success. Pick small tasks like walk daily, or run a mile. These small acts add up over time and builds upon success after success.</p>

<p>This last year I lost 30 lbs. I was running everyday, and switched over to a training plan to run a half-marathon this month. Unfortunately, I got a really bad
cold with bronchitis which totally derailed my running and training. The goal was reachable, but forces outside my control are going to make this goal unreachable
this month. Once I am back to being healthy, I will achieve this goal.</p>

<p>One of the goals I have is to migrate my blog from Wordpress over to Github, and to write more frequently. Let’s see how that works out by the end of 2020.</p>

<p>Happy New Year 2020.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Pulled Pork</title>
	  <link>//2011-07-10-pulled-pork.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2011-07-10T12:34:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2011-07-10-pulled-pork.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/HomemadePulledPork.jpg" alt="Pulled Pork" />
    <figcaption>Pulled Pork</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>The other day my wife made pulled pork. She cooked it in a slow cooker all day.</p>

<p>When I went to cut it up and pull it apart, I did it mostly by hand. It truly was hand pulled pork. It simply melted in your mouth it was so tender.</p>

<p><strong>Delicious!</strong></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Kudzu Blossom Jelly</title>
	  <link>//2011-07-10-kudzu-blossom-jelly.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2011-07-10T10:57:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2011-07-10-kudzu-blossom-jelly.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/KudzuBlossomJelly.jpg" alt="Kudzu Blossom Jelly" />
    <figcaption>Kudzu Blossom Jelly</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>In my last post on <a href="/2011-07-10-moonshine-jelly.html">Moonshine Jelly</a>. I mentioned a neat general store where you can get some unusual food. While I was there, I purchased some Kudzu Blossom Jelly.</p>

<p>For those of you who may not know, <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kudzu">Kudzu</a> is a vine which is native to Japan. It was introduced in the Southern United States in a variety of ways. The largest introduction was from the Soil Conservation Service. It is now considered a week, and responsible for enormous habitat destruction in the Southeastern United States.</p>

<p>Kudzu Blossom Jelly seems to be at least some practical use for it. This jelly is a surprisingly sweet jelly with a nice “wild” taste. I would recommend eating as much as you like and help save the South.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Moonshine Jelly</title>
	  <link>//2011-07-10-moonshine-jelly.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2011-07-10T10:43:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2011-07-10-moonshine-jelly.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/MoonshineJelly.jpg" alt="Moonshine Jelly" />
    <figcaption>Moonshine Jelly</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>There are few things that I must say are quite entertaining about living
in South Carolina. I went into a restaurant/general store in
<a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=Pumpkintown,+SC&amp;hl=en&amp;ll=35.002898,-82.653065&amp;spn=0.033044,0.066047&amp;sll=35.047681,-82.624001&amp;sspn=0.002075,0.004128&amp;z=15">Pumpkintown,
SC</a>.
Yes “Pumpkintown”! The general store called <a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=35.048048,-82.62418&amp;ll=35.047681,-82.624001&amp;spn=0.002075,0.004128&amp;sll=35.00278,-82.65306&amp;sspn=0.018281,0.032015&amp;num=1&amp;t=h&amp;z=19&amp;iwloc=lyrftr:h,11835591884208069584,35.047754,-82.623799">Pumpkintown
Mountain</a>
at the Pumpkintown Opera. They have an unusual assortment of foods
including Moonshine Jelly. I could not pass on such an opportunity to
try such a treat.</p>

<figure class="image">
    <img src="http://4.bp.blogspot.com/-l8swJm9fjU0/Thm58-VKMNI/AAAAAAAABP4/qRqvAMpU3Pw/s1600/ToastCoffeeMoonshineJelly.jpg" alt="Moonshine Jelly, Toast, and Coffee" />
    <figcaption>Moonshine Jelly, Toast, and Coffee</figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I don’t know what I was expecting. I thought it might taste like alcohol, or have a sharp taste. Actually, it has a sweet taste with a pleasant “moonshine” taste. I would recommend trying some if you get a chance. You will not be disappointed, and may even feel like you are getting away with something from them “Revenue agents”.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Volume of a Pizza</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-16-volume-of-a-pizza.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-16T10:58:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-16-volume-of-a-pizza.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <script src="https://cdn.mathjax.org/mathjax/latest/MathJax.js?config=TeX-AMS-MML_HTMLorMML" type="text/javascript"></script>

<p>The general equation for the volume of a cylindrical object is noted by
the following equation.</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">v = \pi r^2h</script>

<p><img src="/assets/images/volume.gif" alt="" /></p>

<p>If a pizza has a radius of <strong>z</strong> and a height of <strong>a</strong>, then the volume
of a pizza can be determined by the following equation:</p>

<script type="math/tex; mode=display">p_v = pi * z * z * a</script>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Reflections</title>
	  <link>//2009-09-14-reflections.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-09-14T20:38:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-09-14-reflections.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/IMG_0023.jpg" alt="Reflections" />
    <figcaption>Reflections</figcaption>
</figure>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Five Lined Skink Eating a Fly</title>
	  <link>//2009-09-14-five-lined-skink-eating-a-fly.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-09-14T20:35:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-09-14-five-lined-skink-eating-a-fly.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I went to lunch today and saw this really neat Five Lined Skink who
caught a fly. The fly is sticking out of its mouth.</p>

<figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/IMG_0034.jpg" alt="Five Lined Skink Eating a Fly" />
    <figcaption>Five Lined Skink Eating a Fly</figcaption>
</figure>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Wacker and LaSalle Bridge Lights in Chicago</title>
	  <link>//2009-09-14-wacker-and-lasalle-bridge-lights-in-chicago.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-09-14T20:33:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-09-14-wacker-and-lasalle-bridge-lights-in-chicago.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <figure class="image">
    <img src="/assets/images/6a0120a56c0ed6970b0120a5c3770b970c-800wi.jpg" alt="Bridge Lights in Chicago" />
    <figcaption>Bridge Lights in Chicago</figcaption>
</figure>

<p><iframe src="https://www.google.com/maps/embed?pb=!1m18!1m12!1m3!1d2970.2713067111554!2d-87.632155!3d41.887021999999995!2m3!1f0!2f0!3f0!3m2!1i1024!2i768!4f13.1!3m3!1m2!1s0x0%3A0x0!2zNDHCsDUzJzEzLjMiTiA4N8KwMzcnNTUuOCJX!5e0!3m2!1sen!2sus!4v1502631801974" width="600" height="450" frameborder="0" style="border:0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Everyone Should Pay Income Taxes</title>
	  <link>//2009-04-13-everyone-should-pay-income-taxes.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-04-13T20:45:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-04-13-everyone-should-pay-income-taxes.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I read a really great <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123958260423012269.html">op ed</a> in The Wall Street Journal from <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ari_Fleischer">Ari Fleischer</a> today. The piece is entitled the same as my blog title: <a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB123958260423012269.html">Everyone Should Pay Income Taxes</a>. Although, I am not totally in favor of some of his political ideas, the premise is sound.</p>

<p>I am a proponent of a flat tax system, or tier max tax system. Let me explain…</p>

<p>In a simple flat tax system, everyone pays the same amount, or percentage, for example 10% of their income. This is simple to determine and pay. If we exclude tax credits, or deductions, it is generally considered fair. Those who oppose the system say its not fair that they must pay if they make more. I contend the person who makes $10,000.00 is more affected than the person making a million.</p>

<p>The other system may be more palpable to some. It requires that everyone pay a percentage of their income up to a maximum amount. For example, we all pay 10% up to a maximum of (for the sake of discussion) a tax bill of one million. Anything above ten million in income is not taxed.</p>

<p>These numbers would need to be adjusted to compensate for our budget requirements.</p>

<p>In Mr. Fleischer’s article he mentions abolishing estate taxes. I agree. Why punish families for growing wealth over generations. This is what America is all about.</p>

<p>He concludes his article with a wonderful quote:</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>“Its funny what happens when everyone pays the bills; Americans may want less spending so they can pay fewer bills.”</p>
</blockquote>

<p>Perhaps this will force some fiscal responsibility to reduce our $2 trillion dollar budget deficits.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
