<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>johnyeary.com/</title>
   
   <link>https://johnyeary.com</link>
   <description>A Caffeinated Java Developer.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>Bhastrika - Bellows Breath</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-bhastrika-bellows-breath.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T15:42:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-bhastrika-bellows-breath.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>A technique for practicing Bhastrika. This is an energizing and cleansing breathing technique.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Start by relaxing the shoulders and taking slow, deep, abdominal breaths.</li>
  <li>Exhale completely.</li>
  <li>Start deep forceful inhalations and exhalations at one second per cycle through the nose.</li>
  <li>Do this for 10 breaths, and then return to normal breathing.</li>
  <li>Continue to breathe normally for 15-30 seconds.</li>
  <li>Start the next round of breathing for 20 breaths.</li>
  <li>Return to normal breathing for 30 seconds.</li>
  <li>Begin the last round of 30 breaths, and resume normal breathing.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> the energized and invigorated feeling after performing this pranayama technique. Increases the metabolism.</p>

<p><strong>Uses:</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>In the morning to start the body and mind.</li>
  <li>During the day when feeling lethargic, or sleepy.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Constraints:</strong></p>

<p>Do not perform before bedtime. It may prevent falling asleep.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Anuloma Viloma - Alternate Nostril Breathing (Sivananda Style)</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-anuloma-viloma-alternate-nostril-breathing-sivananda-style.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T15:39:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-anuloma-viloma-alternate-nostril-breathing-sivananda-style.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>A variation of the alternate nostril breathing technique. This pranayama technique has a quieting effect, and reduces mental turbulence. The ultimate effect of this technique is to quietly reduce the mind to becoming a witness to the process, and make the breathing effortless.</p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> Make sure that the nasal passages are clear before beginning. Using a neti pot to clean the sinuses is a method to ensure that the nasal passages are cleansed.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Close the right nostril. Exhale through the left, and inhale on a count of 4.</li>
  <li>Close off both nostrils, and retain the breath for a count of 16.</li>
  <li>Keep the left nostril closed, and exhale through the right nostril for a count of 8.</li>
  <li>Keep the left nostril closed, and inhale through the right nostril for a count of 4.</li>
  <li>Close both nostrils for a count of 16.</li>
  <li>Release the left nostril and exhale for a count of 8. This completes one cycle.</li>
  <li>Repeat the process for a set of 10 cycles.</li>
</ol>

<p>This technique has a relaxing effect on the mind and body.</p>

<p><strong>Uses:</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>Use prior to performing mantra meditation to calm the mind.</li>
  <li>Anytime your mind is racing.</li>
  <li>When you need to fall asleep.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Constraints:</strong></p>

<p>Do not perform if you need to be alert.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
