<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
      <title>johnyeary.com/</title>
   
   <link>https://johnyeary.com</link>
   <description>A Caffeinated Java Developer.</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor> </managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	<item>
	  <title>The Seven Spiritual Laws of Yoga - Days of the week</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-the-seven-spiritual-laws-of-yoga-days-of-the-week.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T18:30:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-the-seven-spiritual-laws-of-yoga-days-of-the-week.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>The seven spiritual laws and the days of the week for reflection. The book Seven Spiritual Laws of Yoga defines the laws as follows:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Sunday -  Law of Pure Potentiality</li>
  <li>Monday - Law of Giving and Receiving</li>
  <li>Tuesday -  Law of Karma (Cause and Effect)</li>
  <li>Wednesday - Law of Least Effort</li>
  <li>Thursday -  Law of Intention and Desire</li>
  <li>Friday - Law of Detachment</li>
  <li>Saturday -  Law of Dharma (Purpose in Life)</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="law-of-pure-potentiality">Law of Pure Potentiality</h3>
<p><em>Om Bhavam Namah</em> - I am absolute existence.</p>

<p>Thoughts for the Day: Sunday</p>
<ol>
  <li>Cultivate stillness</li>
  <li>Commune with nature.</li>
  <li>Practice non-judgment.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="law-of-giving-and-receiving">Law of Giving and Receiving</h3>
<p><em>Om Vardhanam Namah</em> - I am the nourisher of the universe.</p>

<p>Thoughts for the Day: Monday</p>
<ol>
  <li>Practice breath awareness.</li>
  <li>Cultivate gratitude.</li>
  <li>Acknowledge your needs.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="law-of-karma">Law of Karma</h3>
<p><em>Om Kriyam Namah</em> - My actions are aligned with the cosmic law.</p>

<p>Thoughts for the Day: Tuesday</p>
<ol>
  <li>Witness your choices.</li>
  <li>Consider the consequences.</li>
  <li>Listen to your heart.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="law-of-least-effort">Law of Least Effort</h3>
<p><em>Om Daksham Namah</em> - My actions achieve maximal benefit with minimal effort.</p>

<p>Thoughts for the Day: Wednesday</p>
<ol>
  <li>Practice acceptance.</li>
  <li>Accept responsibility.</li>
  <li>Be defenseless.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="law-of-intention-and-desire">Law of Intention and Desire</h3>
<p><em>Om Ritam Namah</em> - My intentions and desires are supported by cosmic intelligence.</p>

<p>Thoughts for the Day: Thursday</p>
<ol>
  <li>Be clear of your intentions.</li>
  <li>Trust the outcome.</li>
  <li>Practice present moment awareness.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="law-of-detachment">Law of Detachment</h3>
<p><em>Om Anandham Namah</em> - My actions are blissfully free from attachment to outcome.</p>

<p>Thoughts for the Day: Friday</p>
<ol>
  <li>Practice detachment.</li>
  <li>Embrace uncertainty.</li>
  <li>Surrender to the field of pure potentiality.</li>
</ol>

<h3 id="law-of-dharma">Law of Dharma</h3>
<p><em>Om Varunam Namah</em> - My life is in harmony with cosmic law.</p>

<p>Thoughts for the Day: Saturday</p>
<ol>
  <li>Attend your silent witness.</li>
  <li>Acknowledge your talents.</li>
  <li>Serve others.</li>
</ol>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Eight Limbs of Yoga</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-eight-limbs-of-yoga.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T18:16:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-eight-limbs-of-yoga.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <ul>
  <li>Yama</li>
  <li>Niyama</li>
  <li>Asana</li>
  <li>Pranayama</li>
  <li>Pratyahara</li>
  <li>Dharana</li>
  <li>Dhyana</li>
  <li>Samadhi</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Yamas</strong> (abstentions) – truth, non-violence, control of sexual energy, non-stealing, and non-covetousness.</p>

<p><strong>Niyamas</strong> (observances) – austerities, purity, contentment, study, surrender of the ego.</p>

<p><strong>Asanas</strong> (postures) – steady poses.</p>

<p><strong>Pranayama</strong> (breath control) – control of vital energy.</p>

<p><strong>Pratyahara</strong> – withdrawal of the senses.</p>

<p><strong>Dharana</strong> – concentration of the mind.</p>

<p><strong>Dhyana</strong> – meditation.</p>

<p><strong>Samadhi</strong> – the super conscious state.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Chakras</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-chakras.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T18:13:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-chakras.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>The seven Chakras, and their associated mantras.</p>

<p><strong>Sahasrara Chakra</strong><br />
7th chakra, located at the top of the head. It is represented by a 1000 petal Lotus.</p>

<p><strong>Anja Chakra</strong><br />
6th chakra, located in the middle of the forehead. It is often called the third-eye. Mantra: Om</p>

<p><strong>Vishuddha Chakra</strong><br />
5th chakra, located at the base of the throat.<br />
Mantra: Ham</p>

<p><strong>Anahata Chakra</strong><br />
4th chakra, located at the center of the sternum corresponding to the heart.<br />
Mantra: Yam</p>

<p><strong>Manipura Chakra</strong><br />
3rd chakra, located at the navel corresponding to the solar plexus.<br />
Mantra: Ram</p>

<p><strong>Swadhishtana Chakra</strong><br />
2nd chakra, located in the genital area.<br />
Mantra: Vam</p>

<p><strong>Muladhara Chakra</strong><br />
Root chakra located at the base of the spine.<br />
Mantra: Lam</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Nadi Shodhana - Channel Clearing Breath (Alternate Nostril Breathing)</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-nadi-shodhana-channel-clearing-breath-alternate-nostril-breathing.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T15:53:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-nadi-shodhana-channel-clearing-breath-alternate-nostril-breathing.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>A technique for performing Nadi Shodhana, or alternate nostril breathing. This pranayama technique has a quieting effect, and reduces mental turbulence. The ultimate effect of this technique is to quietly reduce the mind to becoming a witness to the process, and make the breathing effortless.</p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> Make sure that the nasal passages are clear before beginning. Using a neti pot to clean the sinuses is a method to ensure that the nasal passages are cleansed.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Use the right hand for this technique. Place the thumb over the right nostril, while your third and fourth fingers are over the left.</li>
  <li>Inhale and exhale through one nostril and alternate between nostrils on each inhalation.</li>
  <li><strong>(Alternate)</strong> Inhale in one nostril, close it off and exhale through the other. Repeat the process alternating back and forth.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>(Alternate)</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>Inhale through one nostril on a count of 4.</li>
  <li>Close off both nostrils for a count of 16.</li>
  <li>Exhale through the opposite nostril for a count of 8.</li>
  <li>Close both nostrils for a count of 16.</li>
  <li>Inhale through the opposite nostril.</li>
  <li>Repeat the process for a set of 10 rounds</li>
</ol>

<p>This technique has a relaxing effect on the mind and body.</p>

<p><strong>Uses:</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>Use prior to performing mantra meditation to calm the mind.</li>
  <li>Anytime your mind is racing.</li>
  <li>When you need to fall asleep.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Constraints:</strong></p>

<p>Do not perform if you need to be alert.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Ujjayi - Victorious Breath (Success Breath)</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-ujjayi-victorious-breath-success-breath.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T15:48:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-ujjayi-victorious-breath-success-breath.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>The Ujjayi breathing technique used to settle the mind and body. Requires the mind to focus on the breathing.</p>

<p>This breathing technique requires equal balance of the breath on inhalation and exhalation. You should partially close the glottis to gently restrict the flow of air. The effect would be like a Darth Vader sound with the exception of the mouth being closed. The sound should not be created by the air passing through the nostrils, but by passing through the back of the throat.</p>

<p>The effect is produces a prompt calming, soothing sensation in the body while forcing your mind to focus.</p>

<p><strong>Uses:</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>Anytime you find yourself becoming upset, or aggravated.</li>
  <li>While performing the asanas to keep focused while moving from one posture to the next.</li>
  <li>Useful during aerobic exercise to enhance respiratory efficiency.</li>
  <li>During cardiovascular workouts to reduce the wear and tear on the body.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Constraints:</strong></p>

<p>None.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Dirgha - Complete Breath</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-dirgha-complete-breath.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T15:46:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-dirgha-complete-breath.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>A technique for performing Dirgha. This is a relaxing and releasing pranayama technique. This technique can be performed upright, or laying down. It is also called three-part breathing.</p>
<ol>
  <li>For the first part of the inhalation, use the diaphragm to draw air into the lower lungs in a smooth rhythmic motion.</li>
  <li>Next, draw air into the middle-lungs by expanding the rib-cage.</li>
  <li>Finally, draw the air into the upper lungs into the collarbones (clavicle).</li>
  <li>Exhalation is the reverse of the inhalation.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Uses:</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>Anytime you need to relax.</li>
  <li>When you need prana to nourish the organs, tissues, and cells of the body.</li>
  <li>Releases tension in the organs by allowing direction of the prana to them.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Constraints:</strong></p>

<p>Do not perform if you need to awaken. This technique slows the body down and roots it.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Kapalabhati - Shining Breath</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-kapalabhati-shining-breath.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T15:44:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-kapalabhati-shining-breath.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>A technique for performing Kapalabhati. This is an energizing and cleansing breath like Bhastrika.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Sit upright and forcibly expel all the air from the lungs. The primary movement is accomplished by using the diaphragm.</li>
  <li>Allow the lungs to fill passively.</li>
  <li>Repeat 10 times in 3-4 cycles with periods of normal breathing between sets.</li>
</ol>

<p>This is another energizing, invigorating, and cleansing pranayama technique.</p>

<p><strong>Uses:</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>In the morning to start the body and mind.</li>
  <li>During the day when feeling lethargic, or sleepy.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Constraints:</strong></p>

<p>Do not perform before bedtime. It may prevent falling asleep.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Bhastrika - Bellows Breath</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-bhastrika-bellows-breath.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T15:42:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-bhastrika-bellows-breath.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>A technique for practicing Bhastrika. This is an energizing and cleansing breathing technique.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Start by relaxing the shoulders and taking slow, deep, abdominal breaths.</li>
  <li>Exhale completely.</li>
  <li>Start deep forceful inhalations and exhalations at one second per cycle through the nose.</li>
  <li>Do this for 10 breaths, and then return to normal breathing.</li>
  <li>Continue to breathe normally for 15-30 seconds.</li>
  <li>Start the next round of breathing for 20 breaths.</li>
  <li>Return to normal breathing for 30 seconds.</li>
  <li>Begin the last round of 30 breaths, and resume normal breathing.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> the energized and invigorated feeling after performing this pranayama technique. Increases the metabolism.</p>

<p><strong>Uses:</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>In the morning to start the body and mind.</li>
  <li>During the day when feeling lethargic, or sleepy.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Constraints:</strong></p>

<p>Do not perform before bedtime. It may prevent falling asleep.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Anuloma Viloma - Alternate Nostril Breathing (Sivananda Style)</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-anuloma-viloma-alternate-nostril-breathing-sivananda-style.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T15:39:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-anuloma-viloma-alternate-nostril-breathing-sivananda-style.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>A variation of the alternate nostril breathing technique. This pranayama technique has a quieting effect, and reduces mental turbulence. The ultimate effect of this technique is to quietly reduce the mind to becoming a witness to the process, and make the breathing effortless.</p>

<p><strong>Note:</strong> Make sure that the nasal passages are clear before beginning. Using a neti pot to clean the sinuses is a method to ensure that the nasal passages are cleansed.</p>
<ol>
  <li>Close the right nostril. Exhale through the left, and inhale on a count of 4.</li>
  <li>Close off both nostrils, and retain the breath for a count of 16.</li>
  <li>Keep the left nostril closed, and exhale through the right nostril for a count of 8.</li>
  <li>Keep the left nostril closed, and inhale through the right nostril for a count of 4.</li>
  <li>Close both nostrils for a count of 16.</li>
  <li>Release the left nostril and exhale for a count of 8. This completes one cycle.</li>
  <li>Repeat the process for a set of 10 cycles.</li>
</ol>

<p>This technique has a relaxing effect on the mind and body.</p>

<p><strong>Uses:</strong></p>
<ol>
  <li>Use prior to performing mantra meditation to calm the mind.</li>
  <li>Anytime your mind is racing.</li>
  <li>When you need to fall asleep.</li>
</ol>

<p><strong>Constraints:</strong></p>

<p>Do not perform if you need to be alert.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>

	<item>
	  <title>Three Types of Food - sattva, rajas, and tamas</title>
	  <link>//2009-10-17-three-types-of-food-sattva-rajas-and-tamas.html</link>
	  <author></author>
	  <pubDate>2009-10-17T12:01:00+00:00</pubDate>
	  <guid>//2009-10-17-three-types-of-food-sattva-rajas-and-tamas.html</guid>
	  <description><![CDATA[
	     <p>I was exposed to a philosophical idea about the three types of food from Indian tradition. Remarkably they seem to make a perfect fit with our modern understanding of foods.</p>

<h3 id="sattva---purity">Sattva - Purity</h3>
<p>These types of foods calm the mind, and sharpen the intellect. These are pure foods without preservatives, or artificial ingredients.</p>

<h3 id="rajas---stimulating">Rajas - Stimulating</h3>
<p>These foods are stimulating. They arouse animal passions, make the mind restless, and make the consumer overactive. They can cause physical and mental stress, and encourage circulatory and nervous disorders.</p>

<p>Examples of rajasic foods are coffee, tea, garlic, heavily spiced and salted items, refined foods such as sugar, and soft drinks.</p>

<h3 id="tamas---inertia">Tamas - Inertia</h3>
<p>Foods that are tamasic result in inertia. They cause the mind to become dull and lazy, reduce motivation, remove focus, and cause the mind to lose purpose. They also cause the body to feel heavy and lethargic.</p>

<p>Tamasic foods are meat, fish, poultry, alcohol, and drugs. Foods that have been reheated a number of times are considered tamasic because the heating process destroys essential nutrients.</p>

<p>Overeating is considered a tamasic behavior.</p>

	  ]]></description>
	</item>


</channel>
</rss>
